ここには まだ来ていない。
They haven't been here yet.
まだか…。
動きがあるまで ここを監視する。
Not yet, huh?
We'll monitor the area here
until there's movement!
うっ！ し… 知らねえ！
I-I don't know...
No way would I tell you even if I did.
知ってたとしても
言うわけがねえ！
…だとよ。 やっちまうか？
That's what he says.
Should we kill him?
拷問なら
イビキにでも任せておけばいい。
We should leave the torture to Ibiki.
やっぱり
暁がいた形跡は ないよ。
No signs of the Akatsuki, after all.
Same here.
こっちも同じ。 ここ数日
人の出入りした形跡がない。
It doesn't look like anyone's been
through here for several days...
まだ ここに来てないのは確かね。
I think it's certain
they haven't been here yet.
どうする？ アオバ。
What's the plan, Aoba?
うっ…！
他の４つの換金所へ向かった
部隊からの➡
There are still no requests for backup
from the units that went to
the other four Collection Offices.
バックアップ要請は まだない。
(ライドウ)ならば 暁との接触は
まだということか…。
Which means there's still been
no contact with the Akatsuki, huh?
いや どうかな…
すでに交戦中かもしれん。
Well, I don't know about that.
They might already be in
the middle of a fight right now.
心配するな。 アスマさんの部隊が
接触したのなら 最も安心だ。
Don't worry.
It'd be reassuring if Asuma's unit
were to make contact with the Akatsuki.
あの人の強さは お前たちが
いちばんよく知っているだろう？
You guys know of his strength
better than anyone, right?
そうですよね。
うん。 シカマルもいるしね。
That's right.
Yeah, and Shikamaru's with him, too.
よし！ 一度 外へ出て
作戦を立て直そう。
All right! Let's head out and
work out another strategy.
行くぞ。
Let's go!
いま一度
すべての情報を整理するとだ➡
Let's sort out all the information
we have right now.
暁は ５つのうちの
いずれかの換金所へ向かった。
The Akatsuki have headed for
one of the five Collection Offices.
There have been no requests
for backup from the other four.
他 ４つからのバックアップ要請は ない。
And they haven't been to
this Collection Office, yet.
そして
この換金所へは まだ来ていない。
ということは…。
That means...
Right.
まだ この換金所へ向かってる
可能性もあるってことだな。
There's a chance
they might still be heading for
this Collection Office.
そういうことだ。
待ち伏せして暁を… 獲る！
That's about the size of it.
We'll lie in wait and grab them.
現段階で考えられる
敵の行動パターンは以上だ。
These are all the possible patterns of
action for the enemy at this stage.
先ほどの作戦どおり
各自 持ち場につけ！
All of you take up positions and
wait as devised earlier!
Yes, sir!
(忍たち)ハッ！
暁… どこに行った!?
Where'd the Akatsuki go?
Climbing Silver
角都 遅かったな。
Took you long enough, Kakuzu!
おせえよ。
Too slow.
まずは１人。
We got one to start.
あぁ～ いってえ… 何だ？ テメエら。
That hurts...
What's with you jerks?
どういうことだ？
急所を貫いたのに…。
What's the meaning of this?
We pierced his vital spots.
グリグリすんなぁ！
Don't push it in deeper like that!
いてえんだよ コラ！
Hey, that hurts!
コイツ… 不死身か？
Is this guy...immortal?
見りゃ わかんだろ！
で… テメエら 何もんだ？
Isn't it obvious?
So...who're you guys?
ん？ そのマーク。
たしか 守護人なんたらの…。
That mark.
If I remember correctly, it's from
the Guardian Shinobi or something...
はぁ～ マジかよ…➡
Are you kidding me?
あんな くせえ換金所に
また行かなきゃなんねえのかよ。
Do I have to go back inside that
smelly Collection Office again?
《地陸…》
Chiriku...
(アスマ)オレたちは 木ノ葉の忍だ。
We're Hidden Leaf Shinobi.
お前ら暁を拘束 または
抹殺するよう 命を受けてきた。
We've been ordered to either
capture or eliminate you Akatsuki.
お前ら暁は ツーマンセルで行動する。
まずは１人を片づけてから➡
Akatsuki operate in teams of two.
Our intention was to take down
one of you first
もう一方を
拘束するつもりだったが…。
and then capture the other.
さすがに
いい能力を 持ってやがる。
But you're pretty tough,
as was expected.
《これが暁か…
なんて ふざけた能力だ！
So this is the Akatsuki, huh?
What insane ability.
これじゃ 影縫いも…》
My Shadow Sewing probably won't...
クッ… フフッ。
テメエら 狙う順番を間違えたな。
You jerks went after us
in the wrong order.
もう１人は どこだ？
Where's the other one?
んっ？
術が はずれた！
The Jutsu's broken!
コテツ イズモ 下がれ!!
Kotetsu, Izumo, get back!
やはり あの真ん中の…
珍しくカネに縁があったな 飛段。
Sure enough, the guy in the middle...
This is a first, you being interested
in money, Hidan.
角都… テメエは手を出すな。
コイツらは オレの儀式用だ。
Kakuzu...
You stay out of this.
I'm going to use these guys for my ritual.
カネは テメエにやる。
I'll give you the money.
《角都… それから 飛段か…》
Kakuzu...and Hidan, huh?
それなら いいだろう…
ただ気を抜くな… 死ぬぞ。
Very well... But don't get careless.
You'll die.
(飛段)だから…
それを オレに言うかよ。
I told you.
Don't give me that.
(飛段)殺せるもんなら
殺してほしいぜ。
If they could  kill me,
I'd want them to.
まぁ… ムリかぁ!?
Well... I guess it's impossible, huh?!
《何のつもりだ？
あの図形…》
What's he going to do
with that diagram?
オレが突っ込む。
I'll charge him.
スキをついて 不死身男を
影縫いで縛れ シカマル。
Shikamaru, exploit an opening
and restrain the immortal guy
with your Shadow Sewing.
少しの時間でいい。
すぐに 首をはねて動きを止める。
It doesn't have to be for long.
I'll cut his head off immediately
and stop his movements.
それじゃ リスクが高すぎっすよ。
アンタらしくない…。
That's too risky.
This isn't like you.
私も一緒に…。
I should go with you.
わからないのか！
それが 今打てる最善の手だ!!
Don't you get it?!
That's the best thing we can do right now!
《アスマのこんな顔 初めて見るぜ》
I've never seen Asuma
look like this before.
ヤツらは オレより はるかに強い…。
These guys are way
stronger than me.
イズモ コテツ。
Izumo, Kotetsu,
you guys back up Shikamaru
お前らは もう片方の暁に
気を配りつつ シカマルの護衛だ。
while keeping an eye on
the other Akatsuki guy.
相手の力が わかっているなら
なおさら…➡
If we know what they're capable of,
then all the more reason
ここは いったん
退いて作戦を立てるのが…。
we should pull out for now
and plan a strategy.
アイツら相手に 簡単に
退かせてもらえると思うな。
They won't let us get away
that easily.
戦意なく逃げようものなら
オレたちは全滅する。
If we try to escape
without putting up a fight,
we'll be completely wiped out...
そうなれば 木ノ葉のリスクは
さらに高まる。
If that happens,
the Hidden Leaf
will be in even greater danger.
敵陣突破の尖兵だ。
It's like sending in an advance unit
to break through enemy lines.
たまには こういう指し方も
できないとな。
Sometimes you have to be able
to make a move like that.
((そういう指し方
嫌いじゃなかったっすか？
I thought you didn't like moves like that.
Just like me...
オレと同じで…。
上手相手に
玉を守るためには➡
Sacrifice is required in order
to protect the king
(犠牲もやむなし ってヤツだ))
when your opponent
is extremely skilled.
《まさか アスマのヤツ
自分を犠牲にして…。
Don't tell me he's going
to sacrifice himself.
一人は能力不明の馬鹿力➡
One of them has great physical strength
with unknown abilities.
一人は不死身…。
One of them is immortal.
Indeed, we don't
stand much of a chance.
確かに オレたちには 分が悪い。
だからって
アスマが犠牲駒になんて…》
Even so, I can't believe Asuma would
use himself as a sacrificial piece.
Shogi?
What a pain...
((シカマル : 将棋？ 面倒くせえな…。
お前が 面倒くさがりなのは
知ってるよ。
I know you're lazy.
だから
面倒なのを避けるために➡
And I also know
that you're good at
planning strategies
for avoiding trouble.
作戦を立てるのが
得意だってこともな。
In Shogi, you can create
a variety of situations
将棋はな… いろんな駒の
個性を活かすことで➡
by utilizing the individual characteristics
of the various pieces.
さまざまな局面を
作り出すことができる。
お前のように 作戦を考えるのが
得意なヤツには➡
It's the perfect game
for a person like you
who's good at
coming up with strategies.
うってつけのゲームだよ。
ルールは だいたい
この本を読めばわかる。
You should be able to
figure out
most of the rules
if you read this book.
あとは やりながらだな。
The rest you'll pick up as you play.
面倒くせえけど こんなの
10分ありゃ 完璧っすよ。
It's a pain, but I should have it
down in ten minutes.
ま… 負けた…。
I-I lost...
手抜かなくて
いいっすよ マジで。
You don't have to go easy on me...
Seriously.
しかし 棒銀とはな。
But I can't believe you'd go
with the Climbing Silver.
It was in this book.
(シカマル)この本に
書いてあったんすよ。
敵陣突破の尖兵だってね。
It said to use an advance unit
to break through enemy lines.
そんなに 負けたのが
悔しかったっすか？
Are you that upset you lost?
いや… 犠牲駒を使った
敵陣突破の尖兵か。
No. Using advance units
as sacrificial pieces
to break through enemy lines, huh?
お前らしい
合理的な考えかもしれんが➡
It seems like the rational kind of idea
you would come up with...
オレは あんまし
好きじゃねえんだよ。
But I don't really like it.
(シカマル)ゲームだぜ？
It's just a game.
I guess.
But the Climbing Silver piece,
まぁね。
だが 敵陣を切り崩し➡
while inflicting a lot of damage
and undermining the enemy line,
大ダメージを与えた棒銀は
犠牲駒となる。
ends up becoming a sacrificial piece.
もちろん 駒のやりとりは
当然だが➡
Certainly taking each other's pieces
is a natural part of the game.
犠牲駒を全面に打ち出した
この定石…。
But to consider throwing away
your pieces to be by-the-book...
オレは そこまで
割り切れないってことさ。
I guess
I'm not quite satisfied with that.
オレだって 言うほど
合理的じゃねえよ。
I'm not as rational
as you say I am.
(アスマ)フッ もう一番やるか。
Shall we play again?
(シカマル)今度は じっくり
棒銀なんて使わねえでな))
This time I'll take it nice and slow,
and I won't use the Climbing Silver.
《敵陣突破…。
Breaking through enemy lines...
Which means these enemies
are so powerful,
犠牲駒もやむなしと
思わせるほどの敵ってことか。
he thinks using sacrificial pieces
is inevitable, huh?
確かに
オレたち中忍じゃ➡
Indeed, we Chunin
would not be pieces
that could put pressure
on these guys.
ヤツらに 圧力と
なるような駒にゃならねえ》
《それどころか オレたちを
守りながら戦うとなれば➡
Furthermore, Asuma would be
at an overwhelming disadvantage
if he had to fight while protecting us.
圧倒的に不利。
We could very well be completely
wiped out as Asuma said.
アスマの言うとおり 全滅もありえる。
What's the best move?
何か最善の手は…。
ヤツらは 間違いなく 大駒だ。
They are major pieces,
no doubt about it.
Bait is necessary to
capture a major piece.
大駒をとらえるには エサが必要だ。
We need bait that's big enough
to make them think
大駒の代償もやむなしと
思えるほどの➡
it's an unavoidable price to pay
for the capture of a major piece.
最善の手と思えるエサが…。
We're not good enough...
to be bait.
オレたちじゃ
そのエサとしては 役不足。
今の持ち駒で
使える戦力となると…》
If we have to fight with the pieces
we have available to us now...
棒銀なんて アンタには向いてない。
The Climbing Silver doesn't suit you.
フフ… ただの捨て駒には
ならねえよ。
I won't be a mere sacrificial piece.
I've got you with me, after all.
お前がいるんだからな。
《情けねえ…。
エサにも圧力にもならねえが➡
How pathetic...
I can't be the bait and I can't put
pressure on the enemy.
But I'll divert the major pieces
like crazy.
オレが 大駒を牽制しまくってやる》
(飛段)作戦会議は終わったか？
Are you done with
your little strategy session?
イテテ…。
グサグサ刺しやがって
いてえな テメエら。
Getting cut up like that
hurts like heck, you jerks.
Divine justice will be handed down
to you jerks
人の痛みを知らねえ クソ野郎には
神の裁きが下るぜ。
who know nothing of the pain of others.
ケッ！ いい武器
持ってんじゃねえか！
You've got a nice weapon there!
アスマ！
Asuma!
クソッ！ 届け！
Damn it! Reach!
《フッ アイツをくらったら
終わっちまうからな》
I'm finished if I get hit by that.
《何度でも折ってやる》
I'll break you over and over again.
チッ！
《シカマル それでいい。
Shikamaru... That's fine.
アイツは 影縫いを警戒しながら
戦わなければならない。
He has to fight while watching out
for your Shadow Sewing.
こっちが有利だ》
I have the advantage.
クソ…。
Damn it!
《確かに オレの影縫いの攻撃が➡
Indeed, my Shadow Sewing attack
is creating
アスマにとって
有利な戦いを生み出す。
an advantageous battle for Asuma.
基本的には 間違っちゃいない。
Essentially, we're not mistaken...
だけどよ
戦いが有利だろうが 意味がねえ。
But there's no point to
having an advantage in this fight.
アイツは不死身。 こっちは
命もチャクラにも限りがある。
He's immortal,
and we have a limit to
our Chakra and our lives.
捕まえなきゃ
こっちの戦いは始まらねえ。
The real battle won't begin
until I grab him.
今は考えてるヒマはねえ》
I don't have the time to think now.
させるかっ！
I don't think so!
しまった！
Oh no!
この構えは…！
That stance!
うおっ！
地陸の術は どうだ？
How's Chiriku's Jutsu?
もっとも 地陸のは
もっとすごいがな。
Naturally, Chiriku's is much
more impressive than mine, though.
クソッ！
Damn it!
飛段 油断するな。
Hidan! Don't underestimate them.
うるせえな。
黙って見てろよ 角都。
Keep quiet!
Just shut up and watch, Kakuzu.
うまい！
Nice!
《さすが この２人は
息が合っている》
As one would expect,
the two of them are in synch.
チッ！
It appears he really is going
to stay out of this.
《どうやら アイツは
本当に 手を出してこねえようだ。
といって
信用するわけにもいかねえが》
Even so, we can't trust him to do that.
さっきのは
惜しかったぞ シカマル。
You almost got him just now, Shikamaru.
んなことより ちょっと
援護してもらえねえっすかね？
More importantly...
Could you back me up?
ケッ！ おめえら 必死すぎなんだよ。
You guys are too desperate.
無神論者どもは
いちばん効率のいい方法で➡
Atheists always try to escape death
with the most efficient approach.
命をとりにくる！
見え見えなんだよ!!
It's totally obvious!
《お前の戦いは
遊びが多すぎだがな》
You play around too much
when you fight.
《今だ！》
Now!
今度は 逃げ場ねえぜ！
This time you've got nowhere to run.
なら よけねえよ。
Then I won't dodge!
チッ… 不死身野郎め！
Immortal jerk!
先に ザコのほうから
片付けてやろうか！
I guess I'll take
《しまった！》
お前の相手は オレだ!!
アスマ隊長！
《コンビネーション技も ピンポイント攻撃も
当たらないなら…》
ヘヘッ…。
《火遁 灰積焼!!》
(飛段)フン…。
《動きを止めただと…？》
(シズネ)不公平よ！ 不公平！
あなたは いいわよね。
スタイルはいいし 美人だし。
(紅)ちょっと飲みすぎよ。
で どうなの？
え？
アスマさんのことよ！
さぁ どうかしら…。
あっ 赤くなった！
もう…。
(シズネ)あぁ うらやましい！
私なんか 一日じゅう
綱手様と一緒だからね。
(紅)あら
立派な仕事じゃない。
でもね
一緒に旅してたときも…。
出会う男ときたら
こ～んなのばっかり！
あ～もう このままじゃ
綱手様みたいに いき遅れちゃう！
あ… ちょっと
それくらいにしといたほうが…。
大丈夫！ 全然酔ってないから。
(紅)いや そうじゃなくて…。
(綱手)シズネ!!
今の話の続き
ゆっくり聞かせてもらおうか。
(シズネ)あひ～～っ!!